Avinash Tingre

Currently working as a Software Engineer at Cerence. Over 3.5 years of experience implementing and supporting large back-end systems in Java. Passionate about innovation, efficiency, and automation.

tingre.avinash@gmail.com ► +91-7741920226 ☐ Pune, India ◀ tingreavinash.github.io ⊕

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

Java, SQL, HTML, CSS

Frameworks

Spring, Hibernate, Angular

Tools

Gitlab, Jenkins, AWS, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Maven

EXPERIENCE

Cerence Pune, India

Software Engineer

Helped build a <u>java application for data extraction</u> task which takes data from JSON and stores it in Excel.

- Design, develop, implement, and support new and existing features in the Cerence <u>Natural Language Processing Server (NLPS)</u> following an Agile Scrum process.
- Test and <u>deploy docker images</u> to Kubernetes.

Netcracker Technology

Pune, India

May 2021 - Present

Mar 2021 - May 2021

Software Engineer

- Modelling of network devices into logical entities.
- Agile development using Jira, Jenkins, SVN.
- Worked with senior software developers to understand the product and technologies used.

Amdocs Pune, India

Software Developer

Oct 2017 - Feb 2021

- <u>Developed a REST API client</u> using Java for one of the major Telecom and Media companies in the USA, achieving seamless communication between the existing on-prem application and DNS management application.
- Streamlined and <u>automated the deployment task</u> on Linux using Ansible and shell script.
- Awarded with "Spot Award" by manager for outperforming the critical tasks.
- Analysed microservices logs via using <u>ELK Stack</u> Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana.
- <u>Used Kubernetes</u> for deploying, managing, and scaling Docker containers.

PROJECTS

Hotfix Search Application (May 2020)

- Conceptualized and developed a web application to explore historical hotfixes provided over a period, which was previously maintained in Excel format, achieving a 90% reduction in efforts for manual tasks.
- Built using Spring Boot, MongoDB, and JSP.

Leave Management System (Oct 2019)

- Created an application to manage the employee leaves. Streamlined the logging process. Which has resulted in 70% increased efficiency to track the historic leaves.
- Used JSP for frontend, Spring Data JPA, Spring Boot for backend service and MySQL as database.

Hotfix Download Utility (Jun 2018)

- Reduced 50% efforts by creating a web application to download a set of hotfixes from Windows NFS.
- Used JSP and Bootstrap for frontend, Servlet for backend service.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (BE - Computer)

Savitribai Phule Pune University - 2017